Edvin Teskeredžić

ABOUT ME

I'm a Master of Electrical Engineering with a focus on Computer Science and Computer Engineering. Proficient tutor and public speaker with 4+ years of experience working in higher education (as a GTA). Currently, I am working as a software engineer on data-intensive mapping and location intelligence applications. Fluent in English and German.



PERSONAL DATA

Date and place of birth: © 15th of February 1997 | Offenbach am Main, Germany

Address:
Phone:

Address:

Add

EMAIL: @ teskeredzic.edvin@gmail.com

Web eteskeredzic.github.io

EDUCATION

2019 - 2021 Master of Electrical Engineering (major: Computing and Informatics),

University of Sarajevo

Master thesis:

Analysis and Application of Deep Learning Methods for Solving the Problem

of Spatial Aliasing \mid GPA: 9.33 (OUT OF 10.00)

2015 - 2019 Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (major: Computing and Informatics),

University of Sarajevo

Bachelor thesis:

Overview and Application of Methods for Obstacle Detection and Avoidance in Unknown Environments | GPA: 8.47 (OUT OF 10.00)

WORK EXPERIENCE:

08/2021 - Present

Software Engineer - Social Explorer Inc.

www.socialexplorer.com

Software Engineer currently focused on developing and maintaining high-performance GIS with integrated mapping, location intelligence, and data-processing capabilities

Duties include:

- Writing maintainble, high-performance code as part of a larger geoprocessing, mapping, and data visualization system (React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL)
- Developing and maintaining web scraping infrastrucutre (Python, Pandas, SQLite)
- Technical mentoring and onboarding of junior engineers

2018 - 2021

(Under)Graduate Teaching Assistant - Faculty of Electrical Engineering www.etf.unsa.ba

GTA for the course Fundamentals of $Computer\ Networks$ (since 2017)

GTA for the course Computer Literacy (since 2018)

GTA for the course **Digital Signal Processing** (since 2018/2019)

GTA for the course Fundamentals of Database Systems (since 2020)

GTA for the course Artificial Intelligence (since 2020)

Duties as GTA: Overseeing/grading laboratory work, writing lab/course materials

07/2018

Laboratory assistant - International University of Sarajevo www.ius.edu.ba

Laboratory assistant for the IUS STEM Camp (Introduction to Data Science in R)

For questions or references, please contact me via e-mail.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

ENGLISH: # Fluent (with a TOEFL iBT score of 115 out of 120)
GERMAN: Fluent (with DSD certificate of C1 level of proficiency)

Bosnian: First language

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Ruby, C/C++, C#

Web Frameworks familiar with: React, Ruby on Rails, Django (basics)

Database: PostgreSQL, PostGIS, SQLite

AI and Data Science: NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Keras Type Setting: LATEX, Open Office, MS Office, LibreOffice

Operating Systems: GNU/Linux (Debian-based), MS Windows

Others: ROS, x86 ASM (basics), Git, Bash, Zsh, CUDA, Go

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

Interests: Software Engineering, AI, Computational Geometry, Graph Theory, Optimization

Positions: Vice President, Embedded Systems Club ETF

HOBBIES: Pub quizzes, Sci-Fi media

Papers

A. Arnautović and **E. Teskeredžić**, "Evaluation of Artificial Neural Network Inference Speed and Energy Consumption on Embedded Systems" 2021 20th International Symposium INFOTEH-JAHORINA (INFOTEH), East Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, 2021, pp. 1-5, doi: 10.1109/INFOTEH51037.2021.9400658.

Available at: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9400658/

E. Teskeredžić and A. Akagić, "Low Cost UGV Platform for Autonomous Indoor 2D Navigation and Map-Building Based on a Single Sensory Input" 2020 7th International Conference on Control, Decision and Information Technologies (CoDIT), Prague, Czechia, 2020.

Available at: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9263975/

E. Teskeredžić, K. Karahodžić and N. Nosović, "Comparison of the Non-Blocked and Blocked Floyd-Warshall Algorithm with Regard to Speedup and Energy Saving on an Embedded GPU" 2020 19th International Symposium INFOTEH-JAHORINA (INFOTEH), East Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, 2020, pp. 1-5.

Available at: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9066330/

Lab Modules

Co-author of laboratory exercises for the course "Artificial Intelligence" on the bachelor's degree programme "Computing and Informatics". The modules cover fundamentals of Python, deep neural networks, expert systems, fuzzy logic, genetic algorithms, and intelligent software agents. Faculty of Electrical Engineering Sarajevo, 2021. Modules are available on the course page: https://c2.etf.unsa.ba/course/view.php?id=120

Co-author of laboratory exercises for the course "Digital Signal Processing" on the bachelor's degree programme "Computing and Informatics". The modules cover basics of signal analysis and digital image processing. Faculty of Electrical Engineering Sarajevo, 2020. Modules are available on the course page: https://c2.etf.unsa.ba/course/view.php?id=41

Co-author of laboratory exercises for the course "Computer Literacy" on the short-cycle study programme "Software Development". The modules cover the fundamentals of GNU/Linux, IATEX, image and audio editing. Faculty of Electrical Engineering Sarajevo, 2018. Modules are available on the course page: https://c2.etf.unsa.ba/course/view.php?id=317